A Guide to the The Virginia Insurance Company Records, 1869-1872
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
The Virginia Insurance Company, 1869-1872
The Library of Virginia
52530
.35 cubic feet (1 box)
The Virginia Insurance Company
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by AXA Equitable Life Insurance Company.
Biographical Information
The Virginia Insurance Company was incorporated by an act of the General Assembly of Virginia passed on 13 December 1865. Located in Staunton, Virginia, the Virginia Insurance Company offered insurance policies for buildings, furniture, and other property against loss or damage by fire. The company also offered life insurance. Another act of the General Assembly of Virginia, passed 13 January 1871, changed the name of the company to the Virginia Banking and Trust Company. The company operated under this name until it was dissolved and sold its properties in October of 1875.
Scope and Content
The Virginia Insurance Company Records, 1869-1872, consists of individual's applications for insurance policies. The applications for insurance contain the name and age of insured, as well as the date and premium of the insurance policy. Applications also contain questionnaires regarding personal information of the applicants, including name of spouse, number of children, residence and occupation, and vaccination and health history of applicants and their immediate family. In addition, applications include two questionnaires to be completed by a personal reference and the family physician regarding the "general health and habits of life" of the applicant. Collection is arranged alphabetically by the applicant's last name.
Contents List
- Baldwin, Robert S., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bickle, John Adam, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Burke, William Aaron, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Caldwill, John Henry, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Campbell, Edward McDonald, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Campbell, James C., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Chelsery, John Roberts, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Dickinson, Crispin, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Dinwiddie, Robert Blanks, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Douglass, Walter C., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Douglass, James Travilla, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Dove, Ashford, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Dudley, Charles Smith, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Dunn, David Campbell, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Dunn, Leander McChesney, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Dunn, William M.S., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Fields, James, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Flinn, John Wallace, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Gorman, William H., 1869 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Griffith, Emerson Jason, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Grim, David Speaker, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Harma, John Alexander, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Harris, Frank R., 1869 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Hodges, William, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Jewell, William Thomas, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Jones, Thomas Scott, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Jordon, William V., 1869 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Kelley, Catherine Mary, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Lathan, Moses Hugh, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Lee, William Peter, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Lynbrook, John, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Magrath, Lewis Oscar, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- McChesney, William S., 1869 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Mitchell, John C., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Nelson, William Jones, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Nowlin, Abner Wendworth Clayton, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Perkey, Lewis Alexander Maxwell, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Pierce, David Stuart, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Sanders, Samuel G., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Sanders, William Campbell, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Sears, Edward Henry, 1869-1870 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Shields, Hannah McFarling, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Smith, Hobart Ray, 1870-1872 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Sowers, William Joseph, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- St. Clair, David Alexander, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Stone, Sallie Cassin, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Strasburg, David Ezra, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Taylor, John Jr., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Warren, Thomas Jefferson, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Wharton, Lyman Brown, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Wilkinson, Hamilton H., 1870 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Wilkinson, John Neal, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Wood, Charles Thomas, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Saunders, W. Campbell (Equitable Life Assurance Society), 1870-1871 (Box 1, Folder 54)